let set25=
    [
        {
            question: `#1. Newton’s third law of motion explains the two forces namely ‘action’ and ‘reaction’ coming into action when the two bodies are in contact with each other. These two forces: `,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) Always act on the same body ',
                    '(b) Always act on the different bodies in opposite directions ',
                    '(c) Have same magnitude and direction ',
                    '(d) Acts on either body at normal to each other ',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: B`,
            exp: `Explanation: Newton’s Third Law Of Motion Force is a push or pull acting on an object resulting in its interaction with another object. Force is a result of an interaction. Force can be classified into two categories: contact force such as frictional force and non-contact force such as gravitational force. According to Newton, when two bodies interact, they exerted force on each other and these forces are known as action and reaction pair which is explained in Newton’s third law of motion. Newton’s third law of motion states that: When one body exerts a force on the other body, the first body experiences a force which is equal in magnitude in the opposite direction of the force which is exerted. The above statement means that in every interaction, there is a pair of forces acting on the interacting objects. The magnitude of the forces are equal and the direction of the force on the first object is opposite to the direction of the force on the second object.,  `
        },
        {
            question: `#2. In a rocket, a large volume of gases produced by the combustion of fuel is allowed to escape through its tail nozzle in the downward direction with the tremendous speed and makes the rocket to move upward. Which principle is followed in this take off of the rocket? `,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) Moment of inertia ',
                    '(b) Conservation of momentum ',
                    '(c) Newton’s third law of motion ',
                    '(d) Newton’s law of gravitation ',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: B`,
            exp: `Explanation: Law of conservation of momentum states that For two or more bodies in an isolated system acting upon each other, their total momentum remains constant unless an external force is applied. Therefore, momentum can neither be created nor destroyed. Law of conservation of momentum is an important consequence of Newton’s third law of motion. Following are the examples of law of conversation of momentum: 1. Air filled balloons,  2. System of gun and bullet 3. Motion of rockets `
        },
        {
            question: `#3. The seat belts are provided in the cars so that if the car stops suddenly due to an emergency braking, the persons sitting on the front seats are not thrown forward violently and saved from getting injured. Can you guess the law due to which a person falls in forward direction on the sudden stopping of the car? `,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) Newton’s first law of motion ',
                    '(b) Newton’s second law of motion ',
                    '(c) Newton’s third law of motion ',
                    '(d) Newton’s law of gravitation ',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: A`,
            exp: `Explanation: Sir Isaac Newton published three laws in the 17th century. In this article, we are going to talk about Newton’s 1st law. This law does an introduction of motion of the object and the force acting on it. In other words, it deals with the motion of an object and its relation to force. Newton’s first law states that: a body remains in the state of rest or uniform motion in a straight line unless and until an external force acts on it.,  Putting Newton’s 1st law of motion in simple words, a body will not start moving until and unless an external force acts on it. Once it is set in motion, it will not stop or change its velocity until and unless some force acts upon it once more. The first law of motion is sometimes also known as the law of inertia. There are two conditions on which the 1st law of motion is dependent: 1. Objects at rest: When an object is at rest velocity (v= 0) and acceleration (a = 0) are zero. Therefore, the object continues to be at rest. 2. Objects in motion: When an object is in motion, velocity is not equal to zero (v ≠ 0) while acceleration (a = 0) is equal to zero. Therefore, the object will continue to be in motion with constant velocity and in the same direction. What is an External Force: An external force is defined as the change in the mechanical energy that is either the kinetic energy or the potential energy in an object. These forces are caused by external agents. Examples of external forces are friction, normal force and air resistance. `
        },
        {
            question: `#4. Which of the following situations involves the Newton’s second law of motion? `,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) A force can stop a lighter vehicle as well as a heavier vehicle which are moving,  ',
                    '(b) A force exerted by a lighter vehicle on collision with a heavier vehicle results in both the (vehicles coming to a standstill ',
                    '(c) A force can accelerate a lighter vehicle more easily than a heavier vehicle which are moving ',
                    '(d) A force exerted by the escaping air from a balloon in the downward direction makes the balloon to go upwards ',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: C`,
            exp: `Explanation: Newton’s Second Law of Motion Newton’s second law of motion can be formally stated as follows: The acceleration of an object as produced by a net force is directly proportional to the magnitude of the net force, in the same direction as the net force, and inversely proportional to the mass of the object. The second law of motion gives us a method to measure the force acting on an object as a product of the mass of the object and the acceleration of the object which is the change in velocity with respect to time. `
        },
        {
            question: `#5. Newton’s first law of motion says that a moving body should continue to move forever, unless some external forces act on it. But a moving cycle comes to rest after some time if we stop pedaling it. Can you choose the correct reason for the stoppage of cycle? \n i. Air resistance \nii. Gravitational pull of the earth \niii. Friction of the road \niv. Heat of the environment Choose the correct option:`,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) (iii) and (iv) ',
                    '(b) (i) and (iii) ',
                    '(c) (i) and (ii) ',
                    '(d) (ii) and (iii) ',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: B `,
            exp: `Explanation: Answer: B`
        },
        {
            question: `#6. Two objects of different masses falling freely near the surface of moon would: `,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) Have different acceleration ',
                    '(b) Undergo a change in their inertia ',
                    '(c) Have same velocities at any instant ',
                    '(d) Experience forces of same magnitude',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: C`,
            exp: `Explanation: Objects of different masses falling freely near the surface of the moon would have the same velocities at any instant because they will have same acceleration due to gravity. `
        },
        {
            question: `#7. The school bags are generally provided with the broad strips because: `,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) It will spread the force of the bag over the large area of the shoulder of the child producing large pressure ',
                    '(b) It will spread the force of the bag over the large area of the shoulder of the child producing less pressure ',
                    '(c) It has become a trend among the students to carry the bags with wide strips ',
                    '(d) It will spread the force of the bag over the small area of the shoulder of the child producing less pressure ',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: B`,
            exp: `Explanation: As we know that pressure is inversely proportional to area, so an increase in area means decrease in pressure.School bags are provided with broad straps to increase the surface area in contact with the shoulders and reduce pressure on the shoulders. If thin straps would be used, then surface area in contact with the shoulders would decrease which will lead to increase in pressure on shoulders.`
        },
        {
            question: `#8. Choose the correct unit for the relative density among the following: `,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) kg/cm ',
                    '(b) unitless ',
                    '(c) kg/cm ',
                    '(d) kg/m3 ',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: B`,
            exp: `Explanation: The difference between the specific gravity and density is that at room temperature and pressure is 1gram per 1 cubic cm is the density of water this density is treated as a standard and density of any other material (usually liquids) is calculated relative to the , this is called relative density or specific gravity. Hence, specific gravity is the ratio of the mass of a substance to that of a reference substance, let’s consider the density of honey is approx. 1.42 grams/cm3, so its specific gravity would be 1.42/1 = 1.42. Notice that specific gravity is a ratio, therefore specific gravity does not have a unit, and hence specific gravity is a dimensionless physical quantity. The specific gravity of a substance will let us know if it will float or sink, it gives us the idea about relative mass or relative density. If,  the specific gravity of a substance is below 1 then it will float and if it is greater than 1 it will sink. Relative density is the ratio of density of a substance to the density of a given reference material. Thus, it is a unit less quantity.`
        },
        {
            question: `#9. The earth and the moon are attracted to each other by gravitational force. The earth attracts the moon with a force that is: `,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) More than that exerted by the moon ',
                    '(b) Same as that exerted by the moon ',
                    '(c) Less than that exerted by the moon ',
                    '(d) Not related to that exerted by the moon ',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: B`,
            exp: `Explanation: Gravitational attraction is caused by the mass of an object. Since Earth is far more massive than the Moon, the gravitational force exerted on the Moon is far greater than that of the Moon on the Earth. An example of the difference: while the Moon causes tides on the Earth, the Earth has the Moon locked so that the same face (minus some wobbling) is always visible from the Earth.,  `
        },
        {
            question: `#10. An apple falls from a tree because of the gravitational attraction between the earth and the apple. If F1 is the magnitude of the force exerted by the earth on the apple and F2 is the magnitude of the force exerted by the apple on the earth, then `,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) F1 is very much greater than F2 ',
                    '(b) F2 is very much greater than F1 ',
                    '(c) F1 and F2 are equal ',
                    '(d) F1 is only a little greater than F2 ',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: C`,
            exp: `Explanation: Answer: C`
        }
    ]